GRETCHEN ARELLANO

Automotive Digital Advertising Professional • SAN DIEGO , 92108 | 619.758.5098

O DETAILS O

2185 Station Village Way Apt. 2433, San Diego , 92108 619.758.5098 glwallace17@yahoo.com

o LINKS o

Linkedin

o SKILLS o

Relationship Building

Consultative Selling

Market Research & Analysis

Brand Building & Campaign
Development

Strategic Planning & Contract Negotiation

Cross-Functional Leadership

PROFILE

Results driven sales, marketing, and training professional with over 21 years of experience in driving business and creating targeted digital marketing/advertising strategies within highly competitive markets. Strategic thinker who can plan and implement sales, marketing, and business initiatives to support corporate objectives. Exceptional communicator with a consultative sales approach, account management, problem solving skills, and a keen client needs assessment aptitude.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Senior Account Manager at Fair Financial Corporation, San Diego

November 2017 — November 2019

- Responsible for identifying and developing potential dealer partner relationships in Southern California including San Diego, South Riverside County, and South Orange County markets.
- Provide in depth coaching and training to dealership personnel to ensure a Fair customer experience is provided and value is maximized for the dealer partners.
- Create and distribute market specific training binders that outline and summarize Fair dealer
 portal functions and deal process. Included step by step instructions from initial order to
 checkout process, scheduling delivery and proper completion of deal paperwork.
- Strategize with Dealer Principals on how to set effective Fair inventory pricing,
- Coordinate deliveries, returns and/or pick-ups of vehicles to and from the dealerships as needed.
- Present & facilitate indirect referral opportunities to dealer via Ally Financial, Dealertrack and Route One.
- Implement and educate dealer on product updates as they are released
- Work collaboratively in a team environment, particularly with the product and marketing
 teams.

Dealer Advocate & Relationship Manager at Lotlinx, San Diego

August 2017 — November 2017

- Cultivate and manage dealer relationships within the western region, provide excellent customer service, and facilitate client retention.
- Conduct onsite visits to auto dealerships within assigned territory to educate and coach
 dealers on the Lotlinx platform, while showcasing ROI, and extending the client relationship.
- Develop and maintain strategic plans to ensure the company's contractual obligations are met, add-on sales opportunities are pursued, and the customer's long-term business strategy is understood.
- Analyze client profiles to understand and recommend new product offerings to increase revenue flow.
- Conduct and prepare competitive market analysis for each client.
- Serve as a consultant to all accounts by understanding industry and product trends, the customer's business activity, and potential impact on each customer.
- Attend & Participate in Automotive industry events to demonstrate and promote full suite of products and services to potential partners.

West Coast Account Manager at Data-Dynamix, San Diego

March 2016 — March 2017

- Manage \$2.5 million in revenue, working with large media companies in providing 3rd party email marketing, display, retargeting, and social solutions.
- Provide comprehensive training for partner's sales team onsite and virtually.

• Maintain consistent contact and relationships with partner's digital decision makers, account executives, and support teams throughout each organization.

Automotive Account Director at iHeartMedia, San Diego

October 2014 — March 2015

- Responsible for planning effective marketing strategies for franchise dealers as well as tier 2
 automotive groups within San Diego county
- Partner with local and nationally based advertising agencies to advise best practices in digital
 advertising campaigns that will meet their clients marketing objectives and align with offline
 media campaigns
- Analyze performance reporting of all programs to identify the best opportunities for optimization
- Establish, maintain and grow current relationships with client base as well as media agencies
- Maintain an organized format on each sales call, covering all-important topics including:
 client market analysis, target consumer needs, benefits sought, assignments and follow-up.

Digital Team Lead, Automotive at UT San Diego, San Diego

January 2008 — May 2014

- Planned and managed digital, print, and TV advertising budgets with Auto Franchises in excess of \$650,000
- Analyzed performance reporting of all programs to identify the best opportunities for optimization
- Managed, mentored and aided in the development of a new business development team
- Worked cross-functionally to create, execute, and measured the performance of highly integrated marketing campaigns
- Experienced in the following Digital offerings: 3rd Party Vehicle Inventory programs,
 Desktop and Mobile Display Banner Ads, Email Marketing, Yahoo.com, Pandora.com,
 Behavioral/Content/Geo-targeted desktop and mobile based campaigns, Mobile websites,
 Geo-Fencing, High Impact & Video banner ads, Pre-Roll, Paid Search, SEO/SEM, reputation
 management, contests, events, sports sponsorship, and social media marketing campaigns.

Customer Sales Associate at AT&T Yellow Pages, San Diego

July 1999 — April 2007

- Generated sales of yellow page advertising within multiple markets throughout California.
- Determined customer needs, present options, and address common objections.
- Consulted with business principals on design features, copy writing, & premium placement strategies

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Business Administration , National University , San Diego, CA

Still pursuing

General Education, Indian RIver High School, Chesapeake, VA

August 1994 — August 1996

June 2001 — June 2006

REFERENCES

Personal and Professional References available upon request

"If people like you, they'll listen to you, but if they trust you, they'll do business with you." – Zig Ziglar